Yes. So, the company is called Riverview
LLP and it operates two enormous farms
in south southeastern Arizona and they
grow alalfa and other feed for their
massive dairy farms and they use a lot
of water. The company has agreed though
to contribute $11 million to help dig
new water wells for the people who live
near their operations. Now, as part of
this agreement, RI Riverview will scale
back crop farming on 2,000 acres and
repurpose the land for grazing, habitat,
or other uses over 12 years in three
phases. Now, for the remaining crops,
the company has agreed to continue its
best practices for water conservation.
It's intended to prioritize residents
who need to replace or redrill
groundwater wells or need to access to
tank systems, water fill stations, or
water hauling. Now, the state's top
legal watchdog called the this agreement
a new president in Arizona.
>> It's a start for me and I suspect it's
just a start for you and I suspect you
have a lot of questions. Um, but you
know, as a daughter of rural Arizona, as
you guys know, I was born and raised in
Prescuit. I don't think there's anything
more important than standing up for
rural Arizona. And I will promise you I
will continue to do that.
>> Yes. So, Maize has also taken a hard
line against the Saudi Arabian company
Fondante, which has been farming alalfa
in western Arizona on state land and
sending it back to the Middle East. We
have reported extensively on that issue.
Now, this is important because
agriculture uses roughly 70% of the
state's fresh water. The Saudi farms and
the farms owned by the Minnesota Dairy
Company are among the largest water
users of agriculture operations in the
state today. Now, Riverview acknowledged
the water issues its community faces,
saying in part it wants to work with
state and local leaders, and that full
response is on afamily.com. In the
newsroom tonight, Austin Walker for
Arizona's